<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Home</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>When to use z-test versus t-test in constructing confidence interval for the mean</title>
      <link>/post/2019-10-28-ttest-versus-ztest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 17:19:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-10-28-ttest-versus-ztest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To construct confidence interval for the mean, we often use quantiles of standardized sample mean distribution. Here, I include a list of cases where I&amp;rsquo;d go for $t$-distribution versus normal distribution quantiles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some of the topics seen at RStudio conference 2019</title>
      <link>/post/2019-01-26-favs-of-rstudio2019-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 19:17:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-01-26-favs-of-rstudio2019-conference/</guid>
      <description>I spent the last days of 2018-19 winter break in Austin, TX where I traveled for RStudio 2019 conference. I attended e-poster session and two days of the conference: Jan 17-18. Below I list some of the topics from the talks that I particularly liked and I think I am likely to benefit from in the future.
Also:
 The official repo with abstracts for every session, workshop (together with workshop files free to download for most if not all of them), and e-poster can be accessed here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[in Polish] Aplikacja na studia doktoranckie (Biostatystyka) w USA: notatki nt. procesu rekrutacji</title>
      <link>/post/2018-09-02-applying-for-phd-in-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 19:17:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-09-02-applying-for-phd-in-usa/</guid>
      <description>W 2015 roku zdobylam tytul Magister na kierunku Matematyka na Politechnice Wroclawskiej. W sierpniu 2016 rozpoczelam aplikacje na programy doktoranckie na kierunku Biostatystyka w Stanach Zjednoczonych rozpoczynajace sie jesienia 2017. Dostalam i zaakeptowalam oferte z Departamentu Biostatystyki na Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health w Baltimore (stan Maryland), oferujacego jeden z 3 najlepszych (ex aequo) programow na kierunku Biostatystyka w USA wg rankingu usnews.com z 2018 roku. W notatce opisuje etapy rekrutacji i podaje swoje obserwacje i wskazowki.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>