<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conflus | Home</title>
    <link>/conflu/</link>
      <atom:link href="/conflu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Conflus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 19:17:23 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hufdd866d90d76849587aac6fbf27da1ac_464_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Conflus</title>
      <link>/conflu/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>/conflu/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 19:17:23 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/conflu/books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#atomic-habits-james-clear&#34;&gt;Atomic Habits (James Clear)&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#sapiens-a-brief-history-of-humankind-yuval-noah-harari&#34;&gt;Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind (Yuval Noah Harari)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;atomic-habits-james-clear&#34;&gt;Atomic Habits (James Clear)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goals are good for setting a direction, but systems are best for making progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;three-layers-of-behavior-change&#34;&gt;Three layers of behavior change&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first layer is &lt;strong&gt;changing your outcomes&lt;/strong&gt;. This level is concerned with changing your results: losing weight, publishing a book, winning a championship. Most of the goals you set are associated with this level of change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The second layer is &lt;strong&gt;changing your process&lt;/strong&gt;. This level is concerned with changing your habits and systems: implementing a new routine at the gym, decluttering your desk for better workflow, developing a meditation practice. Most of the habits you build are associated with this level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The third and deepest layer is &lt;strong&gt;changing your identity&lt;/strong&gt;. This level is concerned with changing your beliefs: your worldview, your self-image, your judgments about yourself and others. Most of the beliefs, assumptions, and biases you hold are associated with this level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With identity-based habits, we start by focusing on who we wish to become.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;process-of-building-a-habit&#34;&gt;Process of building a habit&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of building a habit can be divided into four simple steps: 1. Cue. 2. Craving. 3. Response. 4. Reward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the context of dropping the habbot, these mean:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eliminate the cue and your habit will never start. Reduce exposure to the cue that causes bad habit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce the craving and you won’t experience enough motivation to act.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the behavior difficult and you won’t be able to do it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And if the reward fails to satisfy your desire, then you’ll have no reason to do it again in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;habit-scorecard&#34;&gt;Habit Scorecard&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list of your daily habits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask yourself, Is this a good habit, a bad habit, or a neutral habit? Does this behavior help me become the type of person I wish to be? Does this habit cast a vote for or against my desired identity?
= If it is a good habit, write (+) next to it. If it is a bad habit, write (-). If it is a neutral habit, write (=).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;changing-habits&#34;&gt;Changing habits&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Naming bad habits&lt;/strong&gt;: be lookout for bad habits. Say out loud the action that you are thinking of taking and what the outcome will be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clarity in planning good habits&lt;/strong&gt;: a strategy to change your habits is to fill out this sentence: I will [BEHAVIOR] at [TIME] in [LOCATION].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two-minute rule&lt;/strong&gt;: When you start a new habit, it should take less than two minutes to do. Your goal might be to run a marathon, but your gateway habit is to put on your running shoes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Never miss twice.&lt;/strong&gt; The first mistake is never the one that ruins you. It is the spiral of repeated mistakes that follows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sapiens-a-brief-history-of-humankind-yuval-noah-harari&#34;&gt;Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind (Yuval Noah Harari)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesclear.com/book-summaries/sapiens&#34;&gt;https://jamesclear.com/book-summaries/sapiens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human cultures began to take shape about 70,000 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been three major revolutions in human history: the cognitive revolution (70,000 years ago), the agricultural revolution (12,000 years ago), and the scientific revolution (500 years ago).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans first evolved in Africa about 2.5 million years ago. Prehistoric humans (2 million years old or so) were no more important and impressive than other mammals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Homo Sapiens means &amp;ldquo;wise man.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From about 2 million years ago until 10,000 years ago, multiple human species roamed the earth together. The depiction of man evolving from hunched over to upright incorrectly displays human evolution as a linear trajectory. In fact, the species lived simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans have huge brains for their body size. Human brains account for 2-3 percent of body size, but use 25 percent of energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human kind was very much in the middle of the food chain until 400,000 years ago and didn’t leap to the top of the food chain until 100,000 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most animals at the top of the food chain made it there gradually over millions of years. Humans, however, jumped to the top relatively rapidly. This means that the rest of the food chain wasn’t ready and neither were we. Hence we feel anxious and stressed because we aren’t used to being at the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advent/managing of fire was a game-changer: allowed new ways of processing food (food uneatable before became useful), protection (e.g. from wild animals) and conqueering others (a single woman could lit up a village). Cooking food may have opened the way for the evolution of a smaller intestinal track and a larger brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Homo sapiens most likely developed in the Horn of Africa between 300,000 and 200,000 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two theories of how Homo sapiens evolved: Interbreeding theory and Replacement theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interbreeding theory&lt;/strong&gt;: As some of the first modern humans moved out of Africa, they met and mated with Neandertals about 100,000 years ago (for a period of over 30,000 years). Evidenced by Neanderthal portions of the genome carried by non-African individuals today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Replacement theory&lt;/strong&gt; (recent African origin of modern humans theory): proposes a single origin of Homo sapiens (precluding parallel evolution in other regions of traits considered anatomically modern).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 2010s, studies in population genetics uncovered evidence of interbreeding that occurred between Homo sapiens and archaic humans in Eurasia, Oceania and Africa, indicating that modern population groups, while mostly derived from early Homo sapiens, are to a lesser extent also descended from regional variants of archaic humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this is why Homo sapiens wiped out the Neanderthals: &amp;ldquo;They were too familiar to ignore, but too different to tolerate.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Homo sapiens conquered the world because of its unique language (Cognitive Revolution occurred between 70,000 to 30,000 years ago).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as we know, only Homo sapiens can talk about things we have never seen, touched, or smelled (think religions, myths, legends, and fantasies). The telling of myths and stories allow Homo sapiens to collaborate in large numbers (150+) in extremely flexible ways. This separates us from all other animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chimps can&amp;rsquo;t form groups of more than 50 or so. For humans, the group size is usually 150 or so. Beyond that, you can’t rely on gossip and personal communication. You need something more to get large numbers of people working together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Large numbers of people can collaborate by sharing common myths and beliefs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In academic circles, stories are known as fictions, social constructs, or imagined realities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An imagined reality is not a lie because the entire group believes it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since the Cognitive Revolution, humans have been living in a dual reality: the physical reality and the imagined reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way people cooperate can be changed by changing the stories as myths we tell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Homo sapiens could adapt and change their behavior as soon as they adapted their new belief. They didn&amp;rsquo;t have to wait millions of years for a genetic change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Homo sapiens are the only animals that conduct trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as we know, the humans of 30,000 years ago had the same physical, emotional, and intellectual capabilities that we have today.
Evolutionary psychology claims that most of our psychology was developed during the period before the Agricultural Revolution about 10,000 years ago.
The instinct to gorge on high calorie food is wired into our DNA.
Ever since the Agricultural Revolution, there hasn’t been one predominant way of life for all humans. There have only been options from a variety of cultures.
The dog was the first animal domesticated by humans around 15,000 years ago.
In ancient human groups (over 10,000 years ago) there was very little privacy, but also very little loneliness.
Most of our ancient ancestors had much wider and deeper knowledge of their physical surroundings than we do. They were not unintelligent at all.
The human collective today knows far more overall than the whole population of 15,000 years ago. However, at the individual level we are much more specialized today. Ancient foragers were the most knowledgable and skillful people in history.
It is far easier to pass “unremarkable” genes along today than it was 10,000 years ago.
Our lack of knowledge about prehistoric religions and beliefs is one of the biggest holes in our understanding of human history.
Humans traveling across the sea and landing in Australia was one of the most important expeditions in history. It marked the moment humans cemented themselves at the top of the food chain.
Homo sapiens first made it to America about 16,000 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confluence</title>
      <link>/conflu/land/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 19:17:23 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/conflu/land/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://martakarass.github.io/conflu/cuisines&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cuisines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://martakarass.github.io/conflu/books&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cuisines</title>
      <link>/conflu/cuisines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 19:17:23 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/conflu/cuisines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#cajun-cuisine&#34;&gt;Cajun cuisine&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#indian-cuisine&#34;&gt;Indian cuisine&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cajun-cuisine&#34;&gt;Cajun cuisine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[kej-dżyn]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style of food that was developed in the southern parts of the United States&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It originated with Acadian immigrants, who ended up in the south after fleeing Canada in the 18th century.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;acadians&#34;&gt;Acadians&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Acadians were the original French settlers who came to North America in 17t century&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lived in what is known today as Maritime Provinces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The traditional peasant-style recipes that they brought with them from the French countryside had to be modified to include the ingredients available in the area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These recipes usually involved meat and vegetables cooked together in a large pot of thick sauce. In their new land, the Acadians caught new kinds of fish in the neighboring sea and grew new kinds of foods on land.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, when the Acadians were pressured to swear allegiance to the British Crown in 1755, they refused. More than 14,000 of them were then deported (the Great Deportation). Many of those moved to Louisiana, where true Cajun cooking got its start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;cajun-cuisine-in-development&#34;&gt;Cajun cuisine in development&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After getting settled in this southern area of the United States, the Acadian farmers once again changed their cooking based on what ingredients were readily available to them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This meant their cuisine developed to feature oysters [ostrygi], crab [krab], alligator, shrimp [krewetki], crawfish [langusta], catfish [sum], and redfish [karmazyn] — all of which could be caught in the Gulf of Mexico and the waters of the local bay. This was a stark contrast to the lobster [homar], cod [dorsz], and salmon [łosoś] which they caught in the North Atlantic Ocean outside Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While Cajun dishes are  deeply rooted in seafood, they maintain the Acadian tradition of using whatever the environment provides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Holy Trinity&amp;rdquo; of onion, celery, and green bell peppers are the basis for just about every dish. Additionally, a special roux [zasmażka] is almost always used, and spices are an integral key to developing Cajun food&amp;rsquo;s characteristic flavors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;trademark-dishes&#34;&gt;Trademark dishes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jambalaya &amp;ndash; a dish focused on rice
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pressurecookrecipes.com/instant-pot-jambalaya/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Amy + Jacky Instant Pot Jambalaya&lt;/a&gt;; did not like, too heavy, hot but not flavorful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gumbo &amp;ndash; soup made with okra, sausage, chicken, sometimes shrimp, and file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boudin and boudin balls &amp;ndash; pork sausage and fried pork sausage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rice with gravy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://crazyalanswampshack.com/blog/cajun-cuisine-a-brief-history/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cajun Cuisine: A Brief History&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;indian-cuisine&#34;&gt;Indian cuisine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;trademark-dishes-1&#34;&gt;Trademark dishes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chicken biryani &amp;ndash; a mixed rice dish made with rice, Indian spices,  usually some type of meat, and sometimes also eggs and potatoes
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://spicecravings.com/chicken-biryani-in-instant-pot&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Aneesha&amp;rsquo;s Instant Pot Chicken Biryani&lt;/a&gt;; did not like, added too much water, but also did not appreciate the flavor generally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mishti Doi &amp;ndash; a classic Bengali sweet made with milk, curd culture and jaggery or sugar
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sharmisthadey.com/2014/09/mishti-doi/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sharmistha Dey&amp;rsquo;s Mishti Doi&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrity</title>
      <link>/conflu/integrity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 19:17:23 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/conflu/integrity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-are-the-core-values-that-drive-my-life-and-work&#34;&gt;What are the core values that drive my life and work?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how-am-i-living-and-working-with-integrity-right-now&#34;&gt;How am I living and working with integrity right now?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how-can-i-set-a-higher-standard-in-the-future&#34;&gt;How can I set a higher standard in the future?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-the-core-values-that-drive-my-life-and-work&#34;&gt;What are the core values that drive my life and work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People come and go in our lives, I cherish their good memories, and make my best effort to make life better for people around. But also have to accept the fact that people will come, and people will go. Be happy with the good memories, memories make our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not be slacking. Do not be wasting precious time we are being given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-am-i-living-and-working-with-integrity-right-now&#34;&gt;How am I living and working with integrity right now?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-can-i-set-a-higher-standard-in-the-future&#34;&gt;How can I set a higher standard in the future?&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
