<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conflus | Home</title>
    <link>/conflu/</link>
      <atom:link href="/conflu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Conflus</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 19:17:23 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hufdd866d90d76849587aac6fbf27da1ac_464_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Conflus</title>
      <link>/conflu/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>/conflu/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 19:17:23 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/conflu/books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#atomic-habits-james-clear&#34;&gt;Atomic Habits (James Clear)&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;atomic-habits-james-clear&#34;&gt;Atomic Habits (James Clear)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goals are good for setting a direction, but systems are best for making progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The purpose of setting goals is to win the game. The purpose of building systems is to continue playing the game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;three-layers-of-behavior-change&#34;&gt;Three layers of behavior change&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first layer is &lt;strong&gt;changing your outcomes&lt;/strong&gt;. This level is concerned with changing your results: losing weight, publishing a book, winning a championship. Most of the goals you set are associated with this level of change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The second layer is &lt;strong&gt;changing your process&lt;/strong&gt;. This level is concerned with changing your habits and systems: implementing a new routine at the gym, decluttering your desk for better workflow, developing a meditation practice. Most of the habits you build are associated with this level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The third and deepest layer is &lt;strong&gt;changing your identity&lt;/strong&gt;. This level is concerned with changing your beliefs: your worldview, your self-image, your judgments about yourself and others. Most of the beliefs, assumptions, and biases you hold are associated with this level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With identity-based habits, we start by focusing on who we wish to become.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;process-of-building-a-habit&#34;&gt;Process of building a habit&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of building a habit can be divided into four simple steps: 1. Cue. 2. Craving. 3. Response. 4. Reward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eliminate the cue and your habit will never start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce the craving and you won’t experience enough motivation to act.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the behavior difficult and you won’t be able to do it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And if the reward fails to satisfy your desire, then you’ll have no reason to do it again in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;habit-scorecard&#34;&gt;Habit Scorecard&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list of your daily habits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask yourself, Is this a good habit, a bad habit, or a neutral habit? Does this behavior help me become the type of person I wish to be? Does this habit cast a vote for or against my desired identity?
= If it is a good habit, write (+) next to it. If it is a bad habit, write (-). If it is a neutral habit, write (=).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;changing-habits&#34;&gt;Changing habits&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Naming bad habits&lt;/strong&gt;: be lookout for bad habits. Say out loud the action that you are thinking of taking and what the outcome will be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clarity in planning good habits&lt;/strong&gt;: a strategy to change your habits is to fill out this sentence: I will [BEHAVIOR] at [TIME] in [LOCATION].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce exposure: reduce exposure to the cue that causes bad habit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two-minute rule&lt;/strong&gt;: When you start a new habit, it should take less than two minutes to do. Your goal might be to run a marathon, but your gateway habit is to put on your running shoes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Never miss twice.&lt;/strong&gt; The first mistake is never the one that ruins you. It is the spiral of repeated mistakes that follows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confluence</title>
      <link>/conflu/land/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 19:17:23 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/conflu/land/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://martakarass.github.io/conflu/cuisines&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cuisines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://martakarass.github.io/conflu/books&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cuisines</title>
      <link>/conflu/cuisines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 19:17:23 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/conflu/cuisines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#cajun-cuisine&#34;&gt;Cajun cuisine&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#creole-cuisine&#34;&gt;Creole cuisine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cajun-cuisine&#34;&gt;Cajun cuisine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[kej-dżyn]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style of food that was developed in the southern parts of the United States&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It originated with Acadian immigrants, who ended up in the south after fleeing Canada in the 18th century.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;acadians&#34;&gt;Acadians&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Acadians were the original French settlers who came to North America in 17t century&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lived in what is known today as Maritime Provinces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The traditional peasant-style recipes that they brought with them from the French countryside had to be modified to include the ingredients available in the area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These recipes usually involved meat and vegetables cooked together in a large pot of thick sauce. In their new land, the Acadians caught new kinds of fish in the neighboring sea and grew new kinds of foods on land.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, when the Acadians were pressured to swear allegiance to the British Crown in 1755, they refused. More than 14,000 of them were then deported (the Great Deportation). Many of those moved to Louisiana, where true Cajun cooking got its start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;cajun-cuisine-in-development&#34;&gt;Cajun cuisine in development&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After getting settled in this southern area of the United States, the Acadian farmers once again changed their cooking based on what ingredients were readily available to them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This meant their cuisine developed to feature oysters [ostrygi], crab [krab], alligator, shrimp [krewetki], crawfish [langusta], catfish [sum], and redfish [karmazyn] — all of which could be caught in the Gulf of Mexico and the waters of the local bay. This was a stark contrast to the lobster [homar], cod [dorsz], and salmon [łosoś] which they caught in the North Atlantic Ocean outside Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While Cajun dishes are  deeply rooted in seafood, they maintain the Acadian tradition of using whatever the environment provides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Holy Trinity&amp;rdquo; of onion, celery, and green bell peppers are the basis for just about every dish. Additionally, a special roux [zasmażka] is almost always used, and spices are an integral key to developing Cajun food&amp;rsquo;s characteristic flavors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trademark Cajun dishes include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;jambalaya (a dish focused on rice)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pressurecookrecipes.com/instant-pot-jambalaya/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Amy + Jacky Instant Pot Jambalaya&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gumbo (soup made with okra, sausage, chicken, sometimes shrimp, and file);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;boudin and boudin balls (pork sausage and fried pork sausage);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rice with gravy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://crazyalanswampshack.com/blog/cajun-cuisine-a-brief-history/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cajun Cuisine: A Brief History&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;creole-cuisine&#34;&gt;Creole cuisine&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrity</title>
      <link>/conflu/integrity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 19:17:23 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/conflu/integrity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-are-the-core-values-that-drive-my-life-and-work&#34;&gt;What are the core values that drive my life and work?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how-am-i-living-and-working-with-integrity-right-now&#34;&gt;How am I living and working with integrity right now?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how-can-i-set-a-higher-standard-in-the-future&#34;&gt;How can I set a higher standard in the future?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-the-core-values-that-drive-my-life-and-work&#34;&gt;What are the core values that drive my life and work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People come and go in our lives, I cherish their good memories, and make my best effort to make life better for people around. But also have to accept the fact that people will come, and people will go. Be happy with the good memories, memories make our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not be slacking. Do not be wasting precious time we are being given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-am-i-living-and-working-with-integrity-right-now&#34;&gt;How am I living and working with integrity right now?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-can-i-set-a-higher-standard-in-the-future&#34;&gt;How can I set a higher standard in the future?&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
